Hello English learners and welcome
to English POD. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
Erica, today we are really excited, right?
Yeah, we've got a great lesson
today all about real English.
Exactly English that you
hear in movies and TV shows.
Yeah, speaking of movies, today's
podcast takes place at the movies.
Exactly, and that's why it's so fun today.
Uh-huh.
Okay, great.
So before we listen to our dialogue,
let's take a look at
our vocabulary preview.
vocabulary preview.
In today's vocabulary
preview, we have two words.
And the first word is in considerate.
In considerate.
So Erica, what is it when
someone is in considerate?
If someone's in
considerate, they're not
thinking about the
feelings of other people.
Right, so for example, yesterday I
was on the subway and it was full.
Right, and an old lady was standing there
and no one got up to give her their seat.
That was pretty inconsiderate.
Great, so now let's take a look at
her second word and it's keep it down.
Keep it down.
So why don't we listen
to some examples on
how we use keep it down
so we can understand.
Example one.
Excuse me, do you mind keeping it down?
It's after midnight.
Okay, sorry.
Example two.
I'm trying to study.
Do you mind keeping it down?
Example three.
You might keep it down
trying to watch the game.
So that means be quiet.
Yes, don't make so much noise.
I used to hear this one all
the time from my mother.
I think we all did when we were children.
Yeah.
Okay, so now let's listen to
the dialogue for the first time.
It's going to be kind of fast.
But don't worry about it if
you can't understand everything.
By the end of today's lesson,
you will understand this dialogue.
Don't worry about it.
It's not such a big deal.
No, I can't hear a thing.
Excuse me.
Can you keep it down?
Sure.
Sorry about that.
Someone's phone is ringing.
I think it's your phone.
Did you forget to switch it off?
I don't know.
You're right.
That's so embarrassing.
You mind keeping it down?
I'm trying to watch a movie here.
I hate it when people's phones
ring when I'm watching a movie.
I think everyone gets kind of angry.
But we're going to talk
about this a little bit later.
Why don't we take a look
now at our language takeaway?
Language takeaway.
So the language takeaway is our
most important words for today's lesson.
And our first word today
is not such a big deal.
Not such a big deal.
So when something is not a
big deal, it's not a big problem.
It's not important, right?
Exactly.
Okay, let's listen to some examples.
Example one.
I can't get these files to you by tomorrow.
It's okay.
It's not such a big deal.
Example two.
I'm really sorry.
I'm going to be 10
minutes late for the meeting.
It's not such a big deal.
Peter and Liam are late too.
Now let's look at our
second word and it's switch
it off, switch it off,
switch it off, switch it off.
So this word means to turn
it off to turn something off.
Now we can use it in three different ways.
Yeah, this one is a little
bit complicated because
it changes a little bit
depending on how you use it.
So Marco, I think you've
got some examples for us.
Right.
So for example, I can
say, did you switch off your
phone or you could say, did
you switch your phone off?
Right.
Or simply you can ask,
did you switch it off?
I think this one is a little bit hard.
Let's look at a couple more examples.
Okay.
So I can say, for example, switch off
the TV, switch the TV off or switch it off.
Yeah, I think that's
a little bit more clear.
Yeah.
But you know what, we even had
trouble with that one, didn't we?
We had to do it a couple of times.
Okay.
Now let's look at our last
word and it's, can't hear a thing.
Can't hear a thing.
I can't hear a thing.
Okay, we have some
examples for this phrase.
So let's listen.
Example one.
What's going on in there?
I don't know, I can't hear a thing.
Example two.
What?
I'm sorry, this music is too loud.
I can't hear a thing.
So that's like saying, I can't hear.
Exactly.
I can't hear anything.
It's too loud.
Right.
So now we are ready to listen
to our dialogue a second time.
It's going to be slower.
This time listen for some of the
key words we were explaining.
Those people in front of us
are making so much noise.
It's so inconsiderate.
Don't worry about it.
It's not such a big deal.
I can't hear a thing.
Excuse me.
Can you keep it down?
Sure.
Sorry about that.
Someone's phone is ringing.
Honey, I think it's your phone.
Did you forget to switch it off?
Oh no.
You're right.
That's so embarrassing.
Do you mind keeping it down?
I'm trying to watch a movie here.
Okay, great now with the dialogue slower.
It's really understandable.
Yeah, I think you could catch
those key words a lot better.
Perfect, so now we are ready
to look at putting it together.
Putting it together.
So I'm putting it together.
We help you use a great
phrase in different ways.
And today's phrase is do you mind?
Do you mind?
Okay, so let's listen to
some examples on how
you can use this phrase
in different situations.
Example one.
Do you mind holding my coat for me?
Example two.
Oh, I forgot my wallet.
Do you mind paying for dinner?
Example three.
Do you mind turning off your phone?
So this phrase is usually pretty polite.
I could say to you, Marco, do
you mind holding my coat for me?
Then that's really polite.
Yeah, so what do you mind?
Do you mind are very polite phrases?
But depending on your
voice and how you use
your tone, it could be a
little bit sarcastic, right?
Yeah, it could be a little bit rude if you
say, would you mind keeping it down?
Exactly.
Like we heard in our dialogue.
Yeah, so that's not so polite.
Yeah, exactly.
I mean, in English,
you have to be careful
because your tone of
voice tells the other person
how you're feeling if you're angry,
sad, or just like in any other language.
Yeah, that's true.
So I mean, using a phrase like, do you mind
is a great phrase, but make sure you keep
a positive tone in your voice.
Exactly.
So now that we've talked about all these
great things, we can listen to the dialogue
for the third time, but
it'll be at its normal speed.
Those people in front of us
are making so much noise.
It's so inconsiderate.
Don't worry about it.
It's not such a big deal.
No.
I can't hear a thing.
Excuse me.
Can you keep it down?
Sure.
Sorry about that.
Someone's phone is ringing.
Honey, I think it's your phone.
Did you forget to switch it off?
Oh, no.
You're right.
That's so embarrassing.
You mind keeping it down?
I'm trying to watch a movie here.
So I know that in
different countries, there
are different habits
about watching movies.
Yeah, that's definitely true.
Erica, what's it like in Canada?
Well, in Canada, it's
really common to eat
popcorn and candy and
maybe chips while you're
watching a movie,
but if your phone rings
in the movie theater,
this is a big problem.
I imagine it is.
I mean, I would be upset also.
What about an Ecuador?
Well, in Ecuador and in
South America, usually
people can bring in
food from the outside.
Really?
Yeah, so it's not really uncommon, depending
on the city, to find people bringing in
chicken or some sort
of like really smelly food.
No way.
So you get either really hungry or
really upset, but that's what happens.
You know, I used to
live in Switzerland and
in Switzerland, you would have to
eat before you watched the movie.
There was no popcorn, no soda,
no candy inside the movie theater.
Can you imagine that?
I could not live with
that because the whole
purpose of going to
the movies is to have
some popcorn and relax
and have a good time.
You can't have a movie without popcorn.
Exactly.
Okay, so we've talked a lot about
how to ask someone to be quiet today.
And I hope that you'll go out and try
a few of these phrases in your daily life.
Yes.
I hope also that you visit
our website at EnglishPod.
com and leave all your
questions and comments.
Marco and I are there every day, so
we'll be happy to answer your questions.
But until next time, bye.